<Chapter Label = "Finitely presented semigroups and tietze transformations">
  <Heading>
    Finitely presented semigroups and tietze transformations
  </Heading>

  In this chapter we describe the functions implemented in &Semigroups; that
  extend the features available in &GAP; for dealing with finitely presented
  semigroups.

  <P/>
  
  Section
  <Ref Sect="Words and strings in finitely presented semigroups"
       Style="Number"/>
  (written by Maria Tsalakou and Murray Whyte) and Section
  <Ref Sect="Helper functions for creating semigroup and monoid presentations"
       Style="Number"/>
  (written by Luke Elliott)
  demonstrate a number of helper functions that allow the user to convert
  between different representations of words and relations.

  <P/>

  In the later sections, written and implemented by Ben Spiers and Tom
  Conti-Leslie, we describe how to change the relations of a finitely presented
  semigroup either manually or automatically using "Semigroup Tietze" ("Stz")
  transformations.
  <P/>
 
  <Section Label="Words and strings in finitely presented semigroups">
    <Heading> Words and strings in finitely presented semigroups
    </Heading>
    This section contains various methods for dealing with words, which for
    these purposes are lists of positive integers.

    <#Include Label = "WordToString" >
    <#Include Label = "RandomWord" >
    <#Include Label = "StandardiseWord" >
    <#Include Label = "StringToWord" >
  </Section>

  <Section
   Label="Helper functions for creating semigroup and monoid presentations">
    <Heading> Helper functions for creating semigroup and monoid presentations
    </Heading>
    This section describes operations implemented in &Semigroups; that are
    designed to interact with standard &GAP; methods for creating finitely
    presented semigroups and monoids (see <Ref
    Chap="Finitely Presented Semigroups and Monoids"
    BookName="ref"/>).

    <#Include Label = "ParseRelations">
  </Section>

  <Section Label="Creating semigroup presentations">
    <Heading>
      Creating semigroup presentations
    </Heading>
    It is possible to use &GAP; to create finitely presented semigroups without
    the &Semigroups; package, by creating a free semigroup, then
    quotienting by a list of relations. This is described in the reference
    manual
    (<Ref Chap="Finitely Presented Semigroups and Monoids" BookName="ref"/>).

    <P/>

    However, finitely presented semigroups do not allow for their relations to
    be simplified, so in the following sections, we describe how to create and
    modify the "Semigroup Tietze" object associated with an fp semigroup.
    This object can be automatically simplified, or the user can manually apply
    Tietze transformations to add or remove relations or generators in the
    presentation.

    <P/>

    This object is analogous to the "Tietze object" implemented for fp groups
    in the main &GAP; distribution
    (<Ref Chap="Presentations and Tietze Transformations" BookName="ref"/>),
    but its features are semigroup-specific. All of the functions used to
    create, view and manipulate Semigroup Tietze objects are prefixed with
    "Stz".

    <#Include Label = "StzPresentation">
    <#Include Label = "IsStzPresentation">
    MORE FUNCTIONS TO COME: Generators/RelationsOfStzPresentation;
    UnreducedSemigroupOf... etc
  </Section>

  <Section Label = "Printing presentations">
    <Heading>
      Printing presentations
    </Heading>
    Content to include here: StzPrintRelation, StzPrintRelations,
    etc. Same for generators.
  </Section>

  <Section Label = "Changing presentations">
    <Heading>
      Changing presentations
    </Heading>
    Content to include here: Tietze Transformations 1 to 4
    (with and without checks, with all sorts of different kinds
    of arguments, etc)
  </Section>

  <Section Label = "Converting a modified presentation into a semigroup">
    <Heading>
      Converting a modified presentation into a semigroup
    </Heading>
    Content to include here: TietzeIsomorphism mainly; maybe some stuff on the
    forward and backward maps; also StzPrintGeneratorImages
  </Section>

  <Section Label = "Automatically simplifying a presentation">
    <Heading>
      Automatically simplifying a presentation
    </Heading>
    <P/>

    It is possible to create a presentation object from an fp semigroup object 
    and attempt to manually reduce it by applying Tietze transformations.
    However, there may be many different reductions that can be applied, so 
    StzSimplifyOnce can be used to automatically check a number of different 
    possible reductions and apply the best one. Then, StzSimplifyPresentation 
    repeatedly applies StzSimplifyOnce to the presentation object until it fails
    to reduce the presentation any further.

    <#Include Label="StzSimplifyOnce">
    <#Include Label="StzSimplifyPresentation">

    <P/>

    <Heading>
      Automatically simplifying an fp semigroup
    </Heading>

    It may be the case that, rather than work with a presentation object, we 
    want to start with an fp semigroup object and obtain the most simplified
    version of that fp semigroup that StzSimplifyPresentation can produce. In 
    this case, SimplifyFpSemigroup can be applied to obtain a mapping from the 
    original semigroup to a newly reduced one, and SimplifiedFpSemigroup can be 
    used to obtain a new fp semigroup isomorphic to the first with reduced 
    relations and generators.

    <#Include Label="SimplifyFpSemigroup">
    <#Include Label="SimplifiedFpSemigroup">
    <#Include Label="UnreducedFpSemigroupOfFpSemigroup">
    <#Include Label="FpTietzeIsomorphism">
  </Section>
</Chapter>
